Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/danny-mai (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Structural Engineering Research Skills Sketchulation

Certifications

The National Society of Collegiate Scholars

OHSA 10

Drucilla Shepard Smith Award Engineer In Training

Danny Mai, EIT

M.S. Structural Engineering

Los Angeles, California, United States

Summary

Danny graduated Summa Cum Laude from Oregon State in 2022 with B.S. Architectural Engineering and minor in Mathematics. He spent one year doing research in site response analysis with Dr. Nweke at USC. He is now pursuing his M.S. Structural Engineering at USC.

Danny has worked at 7 different employers since 2017. His strengths are listening, observation, analytics, mathematics, structural analysis, structural design, independent research, and coding.

Danny's time is divided smartly between work, school, and life. Danny believes work-life balance will enhance productivity and life quality. He enjoys working out, playing basketball, reading autobiography, and watching documentaries.

Self-inspirational quote: Be better than yesterday and be your best tomorrow!

Experience

Tipping Structural Engineers
Structural Engineer Intern
May 2023 - August 2023 (4 months)
Berkeley, California, United States

- -Performed 2D structural analysis and design
- -Detailed various structures

University of Southern California Graduate Research Assistant August 2022 - May 2023 (10 months) Los Angeles, California, United States

Study of low frequency peaks in horizontal-to-vertical spectra ratio using 1D ground response analysis

Oregon State University
Teaching Assistant
March 2021 - June 2022 (1 year 4 months)

Undergraduate Lead TA in AutoCAD, Revit, and Navisworks.

Developed course material: Model-In-Place components; Bluebeam, and RFIs

Cupertino Electric, Inc.
Project Management Intern
June 2021 - September 2021 (4 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

Project: Southeast Wastewater Plant – SFPUC Headworks Scope III
 O Created material tracking worksheet, created RFIs and submittals template using VBA Macro, submittals, managed issue logs, instrumentation logs, and schedule updates. Host weekly meeting using these information.
 O Perform material take-off for billing; QA/QC redline drawings and install drawings

Linn County, Oregon Intern August 2020 - September 2020 (2 months) Albany, Oregon, United States

- Project: Albany Courthouse New Switchgear: Built schedules for construction of switchgear
- Project: Expansion of Willamette Health Center: Represent Linn County to work with an architect in schematic design; In charge of writing progress reports to estimate material and timeline
- Project Annex Generator: Recorded field condition and constructed a single line diagram for main system and a diagram of existing controlled devices

Cupertino Electric, Inc.
Summer Virtual Intern
July 2020 - September 2020 (3 months)

Participated in virtual training and learned about 10 topics: estimating, program creation, design assist, BIM & precon, fire rated systems, operations management, technology & software, electrical systems, Q&A session, and people & culture

Oregon State University 1 year 4 months

Laboratory Assistant

January 2019 - December 2019 (1 year)

Corvallis, Oregon Area

 Analyzed the effect of corrosion in reinforcing steel in cementitious material: masonry and concrete

Student Leadership Liaison

September 2018 - June 2019 (10 months)

Corvallis, Oregon

Promote diversity at Oregon State

Build Group, Inc

Intern

June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Project: Chase Bank at Chase Center (Design-Build)
- o Coordinated with the architect to generate details: attachments, light gage steel framing, wall penetrations, etc.
- o Scheduled sub-contractors per 3-week look ahead; Processed RFIs/ Submittals/Material/Install drawings
- o Took on superintendent role on second work-shift in accelerated schedule
- o Procured material, managed delivery, and organized lay-down

Oregon Mainline Paving

Intern

June 2018 - September 2018 (4 months)

Mcminnville, Oregon

- Project: Grant Pass I-5 Expansion project & Tigard I-5 Expansion project
- o Led intelligent compaction bid package (\$40,000)
- o QA/QC; Scheduled rollers for intelligent pavement

Education

University of Southern California

Master of Engineering - MEng, Structural Engineering · (2022 - June 2023)

Oregon State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Architectural Engineering · (2017 - 2021)

Le Hong Phong High School for the Gifted (Petrus Ky)

Highschool Diploma, General Studies · (2014 - 2017)

Oregon State University

Minor, Mathematics · (September 2021 - June 2022)

University of Southern California

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Geotechnical Engineering · (August 2022 - May 2023)